Mss.B.M781 Mss.B.M781
American Philosophical Society
- Autograph collection, Moore, E.M.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the Anthropological Institute [Anthropological Society of London], Nov. 1, 1899; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1823-1913
    Dorset, A.L.S. on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection. Returns photographs and has selected three for publication.
  - Letter to ----, January 1, 1900; 7x3-3/4; Broadbent, W. H. (William Henry), Sir, 1835-1907
    A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete. (see Moore autograph collection.) Praises his father. Refers to the Royal College of Surgeons.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, March 12, 1903; 7x4-1/2; Hill, Octavia, 1838-1912
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has received money and will hope the scheme will go through.
  - Letter to Miss [Aubrey] Moore, Jan. 19, 1905; 7x4-1/2; Alverstone, Richard Everard Webster, Viscount, 1842-1915
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Cannot take action.
  - Letter to J. Aubrey Moore, Oxford, March 17, 1914; 10x1/2x8; Astor, Waldorf Astor, Viscount, 1879-1952
    Typed L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Encloses cheque.
  - Letter to Miss Aubrey Moore, July 21, 1916; 9x7; Turner, H. H. (Herbert Hall), 1861-1930
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Asks if she will paint a garden for him
  - Letter to Miss [Aubrey] Moore, May 10, 1917; 9x7; Turner, H. H. (Herbert Hall), 1861-1930
    Oxford, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for painting, which is lovely.
  - Letter to Miss Aubrey Moore, May 16, 1917; 9x7; Turner, H. H. (Herbert Hall), 1861-1930
    Oxford, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Suggests a subject for a painting.
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 3x7-1/4; Abernethy, John, 1764-1831
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment. (see Moore autograph collection.) Finds writing difficult. Returns letter. Aug. 14
  - Letter to [Sir Henry Wendworth] Acland., Undated; 8x5; Barlow, Thomas, Sir, 1845-1945
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Wishes copyman to speak on vaccination and wishes Acland's ideas on the subject.
  - Letter to Walter T. Shute, Undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bessemer, Henry, Sir, 1813-1898
    Surrey, A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) May 21, Thanks for suggestion for improving the Channel passage.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine Hunt] Moore, Undated; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Bright, W.
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for flowers. Dec. 18.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, [bart.], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1821-1910
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for his kind words pertaining to her proposed institution.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, Undated; 8x5; Cobbe, Frances Power, 1822-1904
    A.L.S. 8p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning the reported "hidden monster of a county family" scandal. Aug. 11.
  - Letter to [the committee of the Covent Garden Theatrical Fund;], Undated; 5x4-1/2; Congreve, William, Sir, 1772-1828
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. Dec., (see Moore autograph collection.) Accepts invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Darwin, Francis, Sir, 1848-1925
    Cambridge. A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for copies of the letters.
  - Letter to ----., Undated; 7x4-1/2; Firth, C. H. (Charles Harding), 1857-1936
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment. (see Moore autograph collection.) "The competition I shall have to face will be even more than I expected."
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine Hunt] Moore., Undated; 7x4-1/2; Fletcher, C. R. L. (Charles Robert Leslie), 1857-1934
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Hopes she can persuade her husband to take the rooms.
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards slides and requests that they be returned by Wednesday morning. Sept. 8
  - Letter to Miss Moore, Undated; 6x4-1/2; Gardner, P.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invites her to see a demonstration of sculpture. Oct. 4
  - Letter to Miss [Aubrey] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hassall, Albert, 1862-1942
    Oxford. A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Gives her examination questions.
  - Letter to Miss Freer., Undated; 6x4; Henslow, E. W.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Accepts invitation to tea.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget, bart.], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Holland, Henry, 1st viscount Knutsford, 1825-1914
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) April 17, Cannot see him unti Friday week.
  - Letter to Mrs. Paget, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
    A.L.S. (see Moore autograph collection.) Is happy to furnish flower for her or for her friends. Refers to Dawson Turner. Nov. 29.
  - Letter to [Aubrey] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hopkins, Ellice, 1836-1904
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Hopes things they are selling will go for Christmas presents. Friendly letter. Dec. 10.
  - Letter to Mr. Moore, Undated; Hunter, William Wilson, Sir
  - Letter to Miss Aubrey Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hutton, William Holden, 1860-1930
    Oxford. A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invitation to tea.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hutton, William Holden, 1860-1930
    Oxford. A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Canon [Aubrey Lackington Moore], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Hutton, William Holden, 1860-1930
    A.L.S. 2p. Feb. 16, (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Jenyns, Leonard, 1800-1893
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning exchange of duplicates of natural history specimens. Nov. 4.
  - Letter to [Lady Louisa Jane Stopford] Brunton, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Lankester, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) June 5, Invitation for her and the doctor to dinner.
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 7x2-1/4; Lankester, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    A.L.S. 2p. Fragment. (see Moore autograph collection.)June 9
  - Letter to Miss [Aubrey] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; McDougall, W.
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) April 13, Encloses check for teaching the children.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Normanby, George Augustus Constantine Phipps, Marquis of, 1819-1890
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Tells him where children's books are published. October 25. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to ----., Undated; 7x4-1/2; Olcott, Henry Steel, 1832-1907
    A.L.S. 1p. Incomplete. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will be happy to talk with him.
  - Letter to [Sir Douglas Strutt?] Galton, Undated; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Osborn, Sherard, 1822-1875
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Interested in naval reform. Dec. 16.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Undated; Phipps, George, Sir, Lord Mulgrave
  - Letter to A[ubrey] L[ackington] Moore, Undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Pocock, Nicholas, 1814-1897
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Cannot help him. Oct. 3
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington Moore?]., Undated; 6x4; Poole, Reginald Lane, 1857-1939
    A.L.S. 1p. Incomplete. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will forward publication if he wishes.
  - Letter to Miss Freer., Undated; 7x4-1/2; Richet, Charles Robert, 1850-1935
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has news on a medium for spiritualism.
  - Letter to Miss Goodrich-Freer, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Sinnett, A. P. (Alfred Percy), 1840-1921
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invites her to his lecture. Nov. 24.
  - Letter to Mr. Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Stubbs, William, 1825-1901
    Oxford, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) States that his brother's work was definitely second class. Dec. 22.
  - Letter to Miss Goodrich Freer, Undated; 6x4; Swanwick, Anna, 1813-1899
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) June 5. Cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to ----., Undated; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Turner, Wm. (William), Sir, 1832-1916
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment. (see Moore autograph collection.) Returns borrowed volume by one of his sons.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine Hunt] Moore, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Tylor, Edward B. (Edward Burnett), 1832-1917
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will come to her garden party alone. July 20.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore., Undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Wakeman, Henry Offley, 1852-1899
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards item and appreciates his sermon.